Guide to Danbury's Third Century Research Collection MS 058
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Janick's Research Materials, 57697
  - News-Times summary, 57860
    - Research Notes, 1881-1886, 57790 (Box 1, Folder 4.2)
      Apr 20, 1886 Town & Borough meeting; Meeting of Hospital Board
      Apr 22, 1886 W.W. Sunderland; Hull & Rogers
      Apr 24, 1886 E.A. Houseman
      Apr 27, 1886 Danbury Hospital; Bell Island Cottages
      Apr 29, 1886 W.W. Sunderland; Alex Wildman
      May 1, 1886 Special Borough Meeting; Sewers
      May 3, 1886 Tweedy; Raymond Family; John Benedict; I.W. Ives Building
      May 4, 1886 Special Borough Meeting; Sewer Report; L.P. Treadwell; A.C. Seely; James Walsh; Edmund Tweedy; D.M. Benedict
      May 7, 1886 Foster Brothers
      May 8, 1886 Danbury and Horse RR; Haines Brothers; Town Hall; Settlement; Rundle and White; Small Grocery Stores and Markets; S. Norwalk Hat Trade; Danbury Tennis Club; L.D. Brewster; James L. White
      May 10, 1886 Hull and Rogers
      May 13, 1886 Harry Cole
      May 15, 1886 St. Peter's Church
      May 17, 1886 Frederick Wildman; New England RR
      May 18, 1886 Nichols and Hine
      May 20, 1886 Ed McPhelemy; C.S. Andrews; J.B. Nichols; D.S. Stevens; Street Paving
      May 21, 1886 I.W. Ives; Morton Gregory
      May 22, 1886 Trimmers Union; Nichols and Hine; Mrs. Eva Baldwin
    - Research Notes, 1900-1909, Undated; 57698 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Summary
      Jan 3, 1900 Kennedy Guards; Annual meeting Board of Trade
      Jan 30, 1900 Figures on hat production
      Jan 31, 1900 Secretary Trustee of Law and Order League; Agents found gambling in progress and at least 14 stands freely selling liquor; At least 60 persons could have been arrested; 15 gambling games stopped
      Feb 7, 1900 Special meeting of Italian Research Club and Italian Socialist Club
      Feb 21, 1900 Special censor agent will be 2 weeks; Agents paid by number of submitted
      Feb 28, 1900 Barber club charged
      May 2, 1900 Italian Socialist Club Meeting
      May 2, 1900 List of census
      Oct 10, 1900 Main street Connecticut House opened
      Oct 24, 1900 Italian Society
      Jan 30, 1901 Expansion of Town; Trustees meeting
      Apr 24, 1901 Danbury News Expanded
      May 15, 1901 Danbury Shirt Company
      Jun 5, 1901 Reverend J.H. Young, Anne Zion Merson; Trustee of building; Alfred Bell; C.H. Merritt: E.A. Housen, T.C. Millard
      Jun 12, 1901 Another long article on how the building of the Danbury and Harlem Railroad will begin very soon.
      Jun 26, 1901 Meeting of Board of Danbury and Harlem
      Jul 31, 1901 Fatal death on Danbury street; Hatters, shortage of staff
      Aug 14, 1901 Interview with C.J. Brown, assorted with Stedel and Siebert who are associated with Danbury and Harlem.
      Aug 28, 1901 Greater prosperity for Danbury in 10 years; Hatters as respectable; Wages better
      Sep 4, 1901 Payday on Danbury and Harlem
      Jan 1, 1902 Carpenters expanding College; Wave of prosperity; Danbury Day, summer of 1901; Interview with 12 local merchants
      Jan 22, 1902 Laying Danbury and Harlem track in Ridgebury
      Feb 5, 1902 Congressman contracts past trustees about need for new building
      Mar 5, 1902 Danbury and Harlem will be purchased and funded by Westchester Tractor Company; Sold because it was too expensive to finish
      Apr 9, 1902 Marconi Society ( new Italian Benefit Society) organizes; 52 members; Meeting of Hat finishers Association (Union); Voted to ratify new bill of 1.00 per day
      Apr 23, 1902 Danbury expected prosperity of last year or two reflected; New Wile Building, new high school, Danbury and Harlem Railroad
      May 21, 1902 Interview Eugene C. Dempster; Conference of Danbury Hat Makers Association
      Jun 4, 1902 Trimmer Association votes to officiate state AFL; 500 people move to Danbury in the past year, " I was to astonished to see how many new people move to the city in the past year."
      Aug 6, 1902 Fur Worker Union
      Dec 10, 1902 Shortage; High prices for coal
      Jan 7, 1903 Hatters Association and high price of coal
      Jan 14, 1903 Association of Hat Makers meeting; Coal situation stabilizes
      Mar 8, 1903 2nd Baptist church organizes Young Men's Debate Club
      Apr 1, 1903 Danbury and Harlem withdraw from Railroad Commission; Request entrance into Danbury; Agree to have Danbury St. Railroad line
      May 20, 1903 Mayor Booth appoints David Bradley as Police Chief.
      Aug 19, 1903 Over 1000 Hatters Mar in Labor Day parade in Bridgeport; Large float
      Sep 7, 1903 New hat company, National Hat Company
      Sep 14, 1903 New High School opens; 48,000 attend fair
      Dec 9, 1903 Danbury and Bethel G + E complete
      Jan 4, 1904 St. Peter's annual report
      Jan 10, 1904 30 year old Italian man arrested for stabbing 2 men on White Street
      Jan 19, 1904 Meeting of Italian Men of St. Peters; Form organization
      May 18, 1904 Captain Torch play at Taylor Opera House
      May 21, 1904 Danbury open and trade shops
      May 27, 1904 Hatbox Shoe Store
      Jul 6, 1904 United Hatters
      Aug 30, 1904 Hat trade picks up; Most shops full
      Oct 19, 1904 Danbury leads state number of cars
      Nov 29, 1904 Letter to editor Samuel A. Doves
      Jan 2, 1905 Large attendance at annual meeting of Fur Hat Makers in New York; Danbury Relief Secretary offers plan to help "worthy poor."
      Jan 10, 1905 Van Gal again declines presidency
      Jan 16, 1905 NHRR approves Highland Drive through Danbury part of development of Poughkeepsie bridge freight route; St. Peters YMCA rents rooms in Hall Building
      Jan 23, 1905 Trial of 3 Syrian of assault on fellow countrymen on Elm St.
      Feb 1, 1905 White St. Railroad Station lighted with electricity for the first time
      Feb 4, 1905 Coal shortages on railroad
      Feb 6, 1905 Industrial census being taken
      Mar 1, 1905 Article on Truman's style in Orange
      Mar 3, 1905 Alderman passes resolution to build new reservoir
      Mar 4, 1905 Good government club favor consolidation
      Mar 20, 1905 Boston real estate firm buys Tweedy's Wools on upper Main St.
      Apr 1, 1905 Tag letter from "Ulysses"
      Apr 8, 1905 Polish mass at St. Peters
      Jul 6 and Aug 9, 1905 Soon 10,000 cars a week crossing Poughkeepsie bridge; Large quantities of freight able to come via Danbury
      Jul 15, 1905 F. Tee negotiating with New Milford to move entire meeting from Danbury to New Milford; Mew Milford and offer to build a $150,000 plant and Tee will start with equal value of equipment
      Jul 27, 1905 Haitsch Hat Co.
      Aug 14, 1905 400 people at Italian assembly
      Aug 15, 1905 Danbury has 640 phones
      Aug 29, 1905 new reservoir described
      Sep 5, 1905 Mayor Labor Day Parade in Danbury; Over 5,000 Mar in 1st state labor parade
      Sep 6, 1905 Danbury Fair to be a "great moral exposition"
      Sep 9, 1905 New reservoir
      Sep 23, 1905 Italian draws gun at railroad bridge construction site
      Nov 9, 1905 Tee to build addition to Railroad Ave
      Nov 13, 1905 Hebrew Cemetery Association (small Jewish population in Danbury) raises money for Russian Jews
      Nov 21, 1905 Hospital crowded
      Jan 1, 1906 Summary of 1905; year of "unexplored prosperity for Danbury"; one of most prosperous in hatting history; State Normal School; Completion of Dabury and Harlem Railroad; Resevoir
      Jan 8, 1906 Danbury Hospital increase in patients, 174-1900, 317-1905
      Feb 6, 1906 Danbury Hat Meeting
      Feb 20, 1906 Office of Labor League of Danbury endorsed Organization of Local Labor League
      February 21, 1906 Local meeting with elective power station of D and B, and G and E
      Mar 20, 1906 Reprints, The Hatters Constitution, or Rules and Regulations Adopted by Central Hatters in Danbury Connecticut
      Mar 31, 1906 Survey of large public building built in past few years: Fairfield County Court House, Danbury High School, Railroad, St. Joseph Church
      Apr 6, 1906 15 year old Italian girl working at Hatters
      Apr 7, 1906 NHRR directs cutting immediate construction of Danbury and Portchester, will tie Ridgefield to Danbury
      Apr 9, 1906 Two new railroads in 1) Danbury track by NY 2) Connecting with Harlem Valley
      May 29, 1906 NY Central extends for Danbury to Harlem
      Jun 7, 1906 C. Augustus Wildmen property on Main St
      Jun 8, 1906 Detailed article on Middle River; Water use
      Jun 12, 1906 WCTU has large meeting at Church
      Jun 16, 1906 Description of new telephone building to be erected on Main Street
      Jul 10, 1906 Main public and private construction in Danbury
      Aug 8, 1906 City council agrees to contribute $1,000 to hospital. First time city contributed to appropriate corporation but now reorganized and city represented on board
      Aug 17, 1906 Sign of Danbury prosperity; 6 new hat businesses started in Danbury and Bethel during summer
      Sep 1, 1906 WCTU rally at Danbury Church
      Oct 20, 1906 Large number of new houses built, 20 constructed; Picture and description of hotel
      Nov 16, 1906 Italian Museum at St. Peters
      Dec 18, 1906 Conference for Danbury and Harlem Railroad
      Dec 31, 1906 List of events of 1906
      Nov 24, 1906 New street car opens
    - Research Notes, 1910-1919, Undated; 57699 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Jan 2, 1917 Frank Lee
      Jan 4, 1917 Goldberger; Foster Factory
      Jan 6, 1917 Petition; Industrial survey
      Jan 9, 1917 American Hatters and Furriors
      Jan 10, 1917 Surgical; Volunteers
      Jan 12, 1917 Balmforth School
      Jan 20, 1917 Public Flag Association; Liberty pole
      Jan 21, 1917 Debate; School building
      Jan 22, 1917 Debate; School building
      Jan 25, 1917 Industrial building; Chamber of Commerce Meeting
      Jan 26, 1917 Ives & Industrial; Ray H. T.
      Jan 29, 1917 Emmet Club
      Jan 30, 1917 Catholic Schools Banquet
      Feb 1, 1917 Chamber of Commerce Meeting; Head of Associated Industrial Sewer; Girls Club
      Feb 2, 1917 Industrial building; Conference
      Feb 3, 1917 Electrical Company expansion; Meeting; Martin Cunningham; John D.; Chris K.
      Feb 8, 1917 Report of Associated Industrial Sewer; DAR; Mayor
      Feb 10, 1917 Military Census; Military service
      Feb 12, 1917 Flag installed; Joseph Twiched
      Feb 13, 1917 Military Census
      Feb 15, 1917 President of Chamber of Commerce; M. Cunningham
      Feb 19, 1917 Census
      Feb 20, 1917 C.I. Roberman Thread Co
      Feb 21, 1917 City Hall
      Feb 22, 1917 Danbury Hat Co.; Chamber of Commerce
      Feb 24, 1917 Debate; DAR
      Mar 1, 1917 Flag raising
      Mar 2, 1917 Patriotic Speech; Patriotic songs
      Mar 3, 1917 Dorrell and Trumpert
      Mar 5, 1917 Danbury Census
      Mar 7, 1917 A. Homer Follow Calderon; Mayor Sunderland; W.M. Redfield; Jones Doran; John W. Green; H.T. Hoyt; C.Stuart McLean; Edward Grunty; Charles Stevens; Nathan Spurs
      Mar 10, 1917 Hill & Taper; A.A. Hodshon Co; Suffrogist meeting
      Mar 13, 1917 City budget
      Mar 16, 1917 Town meeting; Republican Party pledge
      Mar 19, 1917 Guard recruiting
      Mar 23, 1917 Navy recruiters
      Mar 24, 1917 Tweedy Co
      Mar 27, 1917 Sunderland elected
      Apr 2, 1917 U.S.S. Connecticut; Declaration of War
      Apr 6, 1917 Michael Sullivan
      Apr 7, 1917 E.A. Malloy; Meeting of Chamber of Commerce
      Apr 10, 1917 J.D. Plant & Brothers; Chamber of Commerce
      Apr 13, 1917 Town School
      Apr 14, 1917 A.E. Tweedy; G.M. Rundle; C. Malloy; F.B. Dalton
      Apr 17, 1917 SAG Co & J.Boyn Co
      Apr 20, 1917 Malloy & Lee
      Apr 21, 1917 Delohery Hat Co; Malloy; Chamber of Commerce
      Apr 24, 1917 Automobile census
      May 1, 1917 Reverend Calburn; Reverend Twichell; Coal
      May 2, 1917 Motorcycle Club
      May 4, 1917 A. Sullivan
      May 8, 1917 Attorney Henry Wilson; George H. Stalt; United Hatters; Hat Mfg. Association
      May 10, 1917 Flood
      May 12, 1917 Danbury Mfg. Co
      May 14, 1917 Chamber of Commerce; Malloy & Lee workers
      May 16, 1917 City Hall meeting
      May 17, 1917 Lee Plant
      May 18, 1917 Musical Society
      May 19, 1917 City Hall meeting
      May 24, 1917 Patriotic Demonstration
      May 26, 1917 Sewer Organization
      May 29, 1917 Malloy & Sons
      Jun 1, 1917 Whistler & Bells
      Jun 2, 1917 Girls Club
      Jun 5, 1917 Militia
      Jun 6, 1917 League for Women; DHR; Doren Bros
      Jun 7, 1917 Hatters meeting; Girl Scouts; Militart Parade; Patriotic Rally
      Jun 11, 1917 Jewish Nation
      Jun 14, 1917 American Hatters and Furriors
      Jun 15, 1917 Water Department; Flag Day ceremony
      Jun 18, 1917 Red Cross; Parade
      Jun 19, 1917 Board of United Hatters
      Jun 20, 1917 Lee meeeting; United Hatters
      Jun 21, 1917 City Hall meeting; Hatters
      Jun 22, 1917 R.J. Patterson; America Hatters and Furriors
      Jun 23, 1917 Lee; Hat Co
      Jun 25, 1917 Red Cross
      Jun 27, 1917 Parade
      Jun 28, 1917 Parade
      Jun 29, 1917 Parade
      Jun 30, 1917 Parade; Lee Party
      Jul 2, 1917 Mallory; Delohery; Cuff; Hat Co.; Lee Factory
      Jul 3, 1917 Community Council
      Jul 5, 1917 Danbury Home Guard
      Jul 6, 1917 Secretart of Hat Makers
      Jul 7, 1917 American Hatters and Furriors; E.F. Grunty
      Jul 13, 1917 Loewe Case; Danbury Hatters Case
      Jul 14, 1917 Home Guard
    - Research Notes, 1920-1929, Undated; 57700 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Research Notes, 1930-1939, Undated; 57701 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Research Notes, 1940-1949, Undated; 57702 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Research Notes, 1950-1959, Undated; 57703 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Research Notes, 1960-1969, Undated; 57704 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Research Notes, 1970-1975, Undated; 57705 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Devlin's Research Materials, 57709
  - Published Research Materials, 1970s-1990s; 57746
    This grouping of materials includes published materials that were acquired prior to and while doing research on Danbury's Third Century. Many of the items are likely more pertinent to Devlin's earlier work: We Crown Them All.
    - Connecticut History Materials, 1970s-1990s; 57748 (Box 3)
      General
      Connecticut Landscapes and American History by Thomas R. Lewis
      Brass Valley Clockmaking Outline by Chris Bailey
      Connecticut Workers and Technological Change by Robert Asher
      Arsenal of the Revolution by Edward Fales, etc.
      The Polish-Americans of Bridgeport by University Bridgeport
      My Country by My Country Society of Litchfield – Vols: 12-4, 16-2, 17-3, 19-1, 20-1
      New Haven: A Guide to Architecture and Urban Design by Elizabeth Mills Brown
      My Lord What A Morning: An Autobiography by Marian Anderson
      The Story of the Unitarian Universalist Society of Northern Fairfield County, by Reverdy Whitlock
      Fair Haven: A Journey Through Time by Doris Townshend
      Stamford from Puritan to Patriot by Estelle Fienstein
      Windows on the Works: Industry on the Eli Whitney Site by the Eli Whitney Museum
      Fiddlebacks and Crooked-backs by the Mattatuck Historical Society
      Shallops, Sloops and Sharpies: A Maritime History of New Haven, by the New Haven Colony Historical Society
      Short Walks in Connecticut Volume 2 by Eugene Keyarts
      Nathan Hale and the Homestead, by the Antiquarian and Landmarks Society of Connecticut
      Woodbury Connecticut: A New England Townscape by the National Trust for Historic Preservation for the Old Woodbury Historical Society
      A Valley to Preserve and restore by the Housatonic Valley Association
      Norwich Connecticut: A Guide to its Architecture by Stephen W. Harby
      Inside New Haven's Neighborhoods by the City of New Haven
      Candlewood Lake: Past, Present and Future (it's up to you) by Helen Sullivan
      East Haddam Connecticut: A History by Karl P. Stofko, etc.
      The Amistad Incident: Four Perspectives by the Connecticut Humanities Council
      Little Haddam Historic District Report by The Little Haddam Historic District Study Committee
      Norwalk Connecticut: Pictures from the Past by Carl Lobozza
      Talking About Connecticut: Oral History in the Nutmeg State by Bruce Stave, etc.
      Iron Fences of Wooster Square by the New Haven Historic District Commission
      American Funeral Customs: Civil War to Modern Day by the Danbury Historical Society
      The Peoples of Connecticut: Studies of the Cultural Pluralism by Connecticut High School Students by Frank Andrews Stone
      Updating Plan of Development New Milford Connecticut 1986 TPA Design Group
      Historic Houses of Wooster Square by the New Haven Preservation Trust
      Historic District Report East Haddam 1973 by the Historic District Study Committee of East Haddam
      Connecticut's Twentieth Century Pilgrims by the American Revolution Bicentennial Commission of Connecticut
      Hog River Journal, Vol 7-1, Winter 2008/2009
      Artifacts by the American Indian Archaeological Institute, Vol IX-3, Summer 1981
    - General/Regional History Materials, 1970s-1990s; 57749 (Box 4)
      New York Divided, New York Post Special Issue, September 3, 2007
      Regional Geography of Anglo-America by C.L. White
      The Bulletin of the Fort Ticonderoga Museum, Vol IX, Winter 1952
      This is the AFL-CIO, May 1982
      Home of the Brave by Joel Gross
      My Brother Sam is Dead by James L. Collier
      Ideas in America's Cultures by Hamilton Cravens
      Hasty Pudding and Barbary Pirates: A Life of Joel Barlow by Esther M. Douty
      Steamboat Days by Fred E. Dayton
      Everett A. Scholfield 1843-1930 by William E. Parker, etc.
      Country Art in New England 1790-1840 by Old Sturbridge Village
      The "Practicable" Engineer: John B. Jervis and the Old Croton Aqueduct by Larry D. Lankton
      The Rise of Heavy Industry by David Daniel
      1776 National Park Service Guide to the Historic Places of the American Revolution by the National Parks Service
      Official Document Book by the New York State Freedom Train Commission
      300 Years of Germans in America by Heinz Moos Publishing
      Letters to Phil: Memories of a New York Boyhood 1848-1856 by Gene Schermerhorn
      The Lay of the Land by the Rhode Island Historical Society
      Vermont History, Vol 60-4 Fall 1992
      "Village and Community in Early Colonial New England" by Joesph S. Wood Journal of Historical Geography Vol 8-4 (1982) 333-346
  - Miscellaneous Research Notes, 57747
    - Binder of Illustrations, 2012; 57710 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Charles Ives, Undated; 57719 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Clarice Osiecki's Draft, Undated; 57720 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 2007, 2010; 57721 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence and Janick Edits, 2011; 57722 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Danbury, 1950-1959, Undated; 57723 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Danbury Airport, Undated; 57724 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Danbury's Third Century Chapters, Undated; 57725 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Early Draft of "Portrait of a New City", Undated; 57726 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ervie Hawley, Undated; 57727 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "From Danbury State Teachers College to Western Connecticut State College", Undated; 57728 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "The Great Danbury State Fair", Undated; 57729 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - The Great War, Undated; 57730 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - That Hat Industry from 1890-1917, Undated; 57731 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hatters, Undated; 57732 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Hatting in Danbury, 1966, Undated; 57733 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Historical Research Corp, Undated; 57734 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - HVCEO-Map Center, 2008; 57735 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Janick and Note on Retail Revolutions Edit, Undated; 57736 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Memos covering news from 1910 to 1930, 1987; 57737 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1985, 1987; 57738 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Notebook and Notes, Undated; 57739 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Notes on Portrait of a New City and Chapters 1-8, Undated; 57740 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Past Drafts, Undated; 57741 (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
    - Prohibition, Undated; 57742 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Research Notes, 2011; 57743 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - St. Peters Hatting, 2001; 57744 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Women to Vote, Undated; 57745 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Preliminary Planning and Outlines, 2007-2010 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 58645
    - Miscellaneous Preservation, 1979-1987; 58646 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Neighborhood renewal, Kalikow Complex, Housing, Rebirth on Main Street, 385 Orchard in New Haven, etc.
    - Affordable Housing, 1987-1991; 58647 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      low cost housing in Boston; accessory apartments in Westport, CT; receding home ownership; historic Springfield section of Jacksonville, FL
    - Danbury News/History, 1960-2012; 58648 (Box 5, Folder 3-23)
      1960s - new zoning law; 1970s - unemployment tops 10 percent, new city charter, racial tension closes high school for three days, Ethan Allen moves from New York City to Danbury, concerns about deteriorating downtown; 1980s - ending of Danbury Fair, death of News-Times editor Stephen Collins; 1994 - Danbury in WWII retrospective; 1996 - 10-year anniversary of Danbury Fair Mall; 1999 - Danbury Public Library fire, Union Carbide sold, Nathan Ancell dies; 2000 - Future of Route 84, history of Irish in Danbury; 2001 - population grows; 2002 - Trading Post closes after 50 years, history of Lake Waubeeka and NYC firemen; 2003 - Lindburgh and Danbury airport, dangerous intersections; 2004 - Durkin's Awnings - 100 year anniversary; 2005 - Brazilian immigrants in Danbury; 2006 - Danbury as immigrant hub; 2007 - WWII photographer Bill Morrison, Danbury has highest percentage of immigrants in state; 2008 - Danbury buys Taylor Farm, commercial space vacancy in Danbury leads Fairfield County, 30-year anniversary of Interlude, The Great Recession, day laborers; 2009 - Route 84 update and toll plaza study, News-Times stops printing in Danbury, Galante's waste hauling empire AWD up for sale; 2010 - Danbury's 325th anniversary, multiple religions thrive in Danbury, murder trial of Marash Gojcaj begins, rise and fall of Union Carbide, William Goodman dies, 20-year anniversary of Hubble telescope, Joe DaSilva, Lebanese immigrant monument dedicated, Danbury Hospital addition; 2011- Former mayor James Dyer dies, revitalizing downtown; 2012 - growth challenges for Danbury.
    - Miscellaneous Danbury News/History, undated; 58649 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Federer's Danbury Public Library mural, now in Danbury Music Centre; immigration shapes Danbury; area wages; Mayor Jim Dyer testifies in Nicholas Attick lawsuit against Attick former attorneys; smear campaign against Mayor Jim Dyer alleged to be by Nicholas Attick; auction of work by artist Federer, etc.
- Interviews, 57706
  - James Dyer Interview, 2010; 57707
  - Paul Steinmetz Interview 1, 2006; 57711
  - Paul Steinmetz Interview 2, 2006; 57713
  - Jon Chew Interview, 57751
  - Americo Ventura Interview, 57752
  - William Devlin Interview, 57753
  - Donald Groff Interview, 57754
  - Kevin Roche Interview, 57755
  - Morris Feinson Interview, 2007; 58958
  - Mary Ann Frede, January 10, 2011 (Box 6)
    Interview conducted at Holiday Diner
  - A. Peter Daluca, November 11, 2008 (Box 6)
  - Dennis Elpern (1/2), January 21, 2008 (Box 6)
    Tape 1 of 2
  - Dennis Elpern (2/2), January 28, 2008 (Box 6)
    Tape 2 of 2 Interview conducted at City Hall Dennis Elpern was the DAnbury city Planner at the time of the interview.
  - Lenna Reiquez, July 30, 2008 (Box 6)
    Discusses family with emphasis on Gioco Arconti (her brother).
  - Richard Arccont/Gene Eriquez, August 19, 2008 (Box 6)
  - Jack Murphy/Hugh Morgan, November 7, 2008 (Box 6)